# ANCA SIMON

## FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

C# | ASP.NET CORE | SOL | JAVASCRIPT | REACT

ANCARSIMON@GMAIL.COM

https://asimonbio.web.app

https://www.linkedin.com/in/anca-simon/

https://github.com/ancasimon

# **ABOUT ME**

One of the most vivid memories in my BA experience is the demo where we saw the first iteration of a project I had owned from discovery and market research through mockups, requirements, and now development. Seeing an actual program where before there had been just words on paper (well, on screen) was amazing! Today, I am a developer because of that moment. I love solving technical and business problems and helping users leverage technology to enhance results.

### PROJECTS @ NSS

## UNLIMITED

Make learning a musical instrument fun and engaging! A full-stack CRUD application built with C#. ASP .NET Core MVC. SQL database. HTTP-based APIs, and a single-page React application with Firebase authentication, and deployed with Azure, this app allows parents of budding musicians to create customized practice plans, browse through a database of games for ideas, which they can filter based on their needs. select games to include in each plan, and track their own practice notes and completions. It will make them want to practice!

Technologies: API, ASP. NET Core MVC, Axios, Bootstrap, C#, CSS, ES6 Modules, ESLint. Firebase, HTML5, JavaScript, React, React Router reactstrap, SQL, SSMS

https://github.com/ancasimon/backendcapstone

## GEARUP

GearUp eliminates the stress of packing for outdoor adventures! A single-page React application with CRUD functionality, using a realtime JSON server, it allows you to manage your camping gear and trips. Users can create records for their gear, edit, and delete them as well as filter the gear list. They can create and edit trips and quickly put together packing lists for each trip. Time to get outside!

Technologies: Axios, Bootstrap, CSS, ES6 Modules, Firebase, Google login authentication, HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, JSON, React, React Router, reactstrap, REST API, Sass, Webpack

https://github.com/ancasimon/front-endcapstone

## **TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE**

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### Nashville Software School | 2020-2021

Intensive accelerated software development program, teaching full-stack technologies through the creation of applications in group and individual settings

Skills: API; ASP .NET Core MVC; Azure; Bootstrap; C#; CSS; GitHub; HTML5; JavaScript; ¡Query; SQL; SSMS; .NET Core; React; Scrum/Agile

- Learned object-oriented programming fundamentals and development best practices
- Built full-stack applications using C#, ASP .NET Core MVC, HTTP-based APIs, SQL database, Azure, and a React frontend application
- Created single-page applications using React, React Router, reactstrap, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, and REST APIs with a JSON server
- Used Git and GitHub for version control

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **BUSINESS ANALYST**

Contracted with TEKsystems for the TN Department of Human Services | 2016 Information technology and services recruiting organization

- Worked closely with business users to document workflows and business and technical requirements to transition current COBOL software application to Oracle **Forms**
- Provided visibility into project progress and commitments by managing project metrics, leading the implementation of Agile methodology, and acting as the Scrum Master for the development team. Used Team Foundation Server (TFS) to manage the backlog.

#### **BUSINESS ANALYST & PRODUCT MANAGER**

## UL Workplace Health & Safety | 2010-2016

Business unit of Underwriters Laboratories, providing software applications and e-learning training to help improve the safety of workers across diverse industries

- Drove product strategy by working closely with customers, support, sales, marketing, solutions consultants, and the management team to define the product roadmap
- Managed the end-to-end Product Management process that spans market needs identification to product development to product launch and support
- Ensured product roadmap goals were successfully implemented by collaborating effectively with the development teams
- Planned release schedule, deliverables, goals, and milestones, using Rally. Defined technical and business requirements and maintained project documentation
- Increased new sales and customer expansions by providing support to the Sales team, helping with RFPs, conducting demos, and creating roadmap collateral

#### **TECHNICAL WRITER & TEAM LEAD**

Epic Systems Corporation | 2005-2010

Healthcare software provider, offering a centralized site for a patient's information

- Helped customers become successful users of the software applications by producing a wide variety of user materials, leading customer sessions, and providing onsite go-live assistance
- Led the reporting data warehouse initiative to provide users more actionable reporting on clinical and billing data.

# EDUCATION

Nashville Software School, 2020-21: Certificate, Full-Stack Software Development Middle Tennessee State University: MA English Lipscomb University: BA English